You don't need to fight
in the team tournament.
（小関(おぜき)）
お前は団体戦 出なくていいよ
（火ノ丸(ひのまる)）グッ…
You're hurt, aren't you?
We're not falling for it again!
（小関）痛めてんだろう？
そう何度もダマされねえよ！
（礼奈(れいな)）あっ…
I'm fine! This is nothing.
（火ノ丸）
大丈夫じゃ　これくらい何とも…
Tsuji's calling a taxi right now.
（小関）今 辻(つじ)が
タクシー呼びに行ってるから—
You're going to the hospital.
お前は病院に行くんだ
（火ノ丸）うん？
（小関）まだ終わってないぞ 潮(うしお)
You're not done yet, Ushio.
Your dream of joining the pro league
may come true in the team tournament.
（小関）プロになるっていう
お前の夢も—
団体戦で
かなえられるかもしれないんだから
Bout 15
"National Treasure is Delicious"
Kanie Clinic
Hey, Doc! It's Shibakiyama!
（柴木山(しばきやま)）
お〜い 先生　柴木山です
（蟹江(かにえ)）うるさいな…
（戸の開く音）
I heard you, I heard you...
I've got a wretched hangover.
Keep it down, will ya, Kaorucchi?
（蟹江）こっちは二日酔いなんだ
静かに頼むぜ 薫(かおる)っち
（火ノ丸）だ… 大丈夫か？
I-Is this a good idea?
He... pushed me out of the ring?
（金盛(かなもり)）こいつが 寄り切りだと？
It's not like he gave up on on strikes.
（瀬良(せら)）別に 突き押しを
捨てたわけじゃない
It's just that, now, Tenma's
a national treasure at grappling, too.
ただ 今の典馬(てんま)は組んでも国宝だ
That concludes today's individual bouts.
（アナウンス）
本日の個人戦は全て終了しました
これより
団体予選 １回戦を開始します
We will now begin the team
tournament preliminary bouts.
（蟹江）え〜 “潮火ノ丸君 15歳”
Ushio Hinomaru-kun, 15 years of age.
ワシん家(ち)よりボロい
This dump's even more
rundown than my place.
ひゃ… 152センチ！？　小さっ！
Only 152 cm tall?!
That's tiny!
As a matter of fact,
I'm aiming at becoming a pro.
実は ワシ プロを目指してまして…
はぁ？
君ね 新弟子検査って知ってる？
Hey, kid, don't you know
about the physical exam?
You need to take your head out the clouds.
まったく
“冗談は よし子ちゃん”だよ
僕だって 暇じゃないの
I'm a busy man.
Look at how sunny it is out there.
見たまえよ　いい天気じゃないか
照りつける太陽
Shine on, Mr. Sun.
青い海 白い砂浜
そして 小麦色の肌
Blue sea... White, sandy beaches...
And skin the color of wheat!
ほら 夏が僕を呼んでいる
フフフフッ…
Summer's calling out to me!
（柴木山）腕は確かなんだけどね…
He's actually a very good doctor, honest.
So that's how it is. See ya.
（蟹江）
そういうわけでね　じゃあね
E-Excuse me!
（火ノ丸）あ… あの…
（蟹江）な… 何だい？
Now what?
Please! My team's waiting for me!
お願いします！
仲間たちが待っとるんです！
Our luck has stunk today.
（礼奈）どんだけクジ運ないのよ
Devoted Souls are Victorious
Kanazawa Kita High School
Sumo Club
We drew last year's third-placed
team in the first round.
１回戦で いきなり
去年の全国３位となんて…
And three of their current lineup
took part in that tournament.
（千鶴子(ちづこ)）しかも 今年は去年の
団体メンバーが３人も残っています
その中のひとりは
あの国宝 日景(ひかげ)典馬
Including national treasure Hikage Tenma.
彼がいますからね
He'll be competing, too.
In other words, we're in serious trouble.
要するに 大ピンチってことね
（アナウンス）続きまして
東 大太刀(おおだち)高校　西 金沢北(かなざわきた)高校
For the next match, on the
east side, Odachi High School.
On the west side,
Kanazawa Kita High School.
（佑真(ゆうま)）さあ いってこい！
Okay, go get ‘em!
First bout: on the east side, Ozeki-kun.
（アナウンス）先鋒戦(せんぽうせん) 東 小関君
（小関）はい！
Yeah!
On the west side, Aizawa-kun.
（アナウンス）西 相沢(あいざわ)君
Captain Aizawa!
（部員）相沢主将！
（部員）ファイト！
Fight!
The "Swift Foot Pull": Aizawa Ryo.
“疾風の引き足” 相沢亮(りょう)
Although he's not the biggest,
he is captain of the formidable Kita High.
細身ながら 強豪 北高の
主将を務める その実力は本物です
He's very skilled.
I don't see any point in wasting my time.
（蟹江）
僕はね ムダなことは したくないの
"Wasting"?
ムダ？
１回戦の相手 金沢北高でしょう？
Your team's up against
Kanazawa Kita High first, right?
君は 本気で
仲間たちが勝つと思ってるの？
Do you really think your team can win?
Huh? What's this?
（蟹江）あれ？　あれあれ？
僕 おかしなこと言ってる？
Didn't you understand the question?
Come to think of it,
I guess they could lose...
（火ノ丸）あっ いや…
確かに 言われてみれば
そういう可能性もあるんか
Huh?
I wasn't worried about that in the slightest.
そっちの心配は
全然しとらんかったです
（審判）はっきよい！
Spirit!
（小関）ンンッ！
（相沢）ウワッ！
I'll admit, it was a shock when he said
I wasn't needed in the team tournament.
確かに 団体戦に
出なくていいと言われたときは—
ショックじゃったし 不安もあった
It made me feel uneasy.
でも 部長の話を最後まで聞いて
みんなの目を見たとき—
But after hearing the captain out,
and seeing the looks in their eyes...
不思議と そこには
何の不安もなかったんス
I suddenly felt oddly relaxed about it all.
It's not about how they need my help
or how they can't win without me.
助けようとか ワシがいなきゃとか
そういうんじゃない
また みんなと戦いたい
今は ただ そう思っとるんです
I just want to fight with them again.
That's the only thing on my mind right now.
腕 見せてみな
Show me your arm.
It'd be better for your sumo career in
the long-term if you sat this one out.
やめたほうがいい
この先の選手生活を考えたらな
At least, that's what any doctor with
an ounce of common sense would say!
…と
良識のある医者なら言うだろうな
You're all so bright-eyed and bushy-tailed!
…たく よう
お前ら いい青春してんな！
Give me some of that exuberance!
俺も 一枚かませろや！
（蟹江）
今まで 大勢の力士を診てきた
I've treated a lot of
sumo wrestlers in my time.
Some were too beat up to even get
into the ring, but they still came to me.
ボロボロで 土俵に
上がれる状態じゃねえヤツが—
それでも 俺を頼って やって来る
お前の腕なんざ 屁(へ)みたいなもんさ
Treating your arm will be
as easy as passing gas.
（火ノ丸）うん？
な… 何じゃ！？　この部屋は
Wh-What kind of room is this?!
I'm taken aback every time I see this room.
（柴木山）いつ見ても すごいな
You should put some money
toward fixing up your sign.
この金で せめて
看板くらいは直せばいいのに
The sign's fine.
いいんだよ
放っといたって客は来る
I still get plenty of patients.
I'll make that arm of yours useful.
その腕 使えるようにしてやるよ
I never expected Ozeki-kun to be so dominant.
（寺原(てらはら)）いや しかし ここまで
小関君が圧倒するなんて—
びっくりッスよね
It was partly due to the matchup,
but he showed beating you was no fluke.
（金盛）相性もあるだろうが
お前を倒しただけのことはあるな
He's looking even better
now than he did then.
（真田(さなだ)）
むしろ あんときよりノッてるよ
I thought Onimaru's absence
would weigh heavy on him,
鬼丸(おにまる)の不在で
意気消沈するかと思ったが—
but it seems like it's only
made him more determined.
逆に発憤材料になったみてえだ
His expression and his technique
are brimming with spirit.
表情 取り口から
気迫が みなぎってる
His face screams,
"I'm Dachi High's captain!"
“ダチ高の部長は俺だ”って顔だ
Looks like your favorite fighter's up next.
さ〜て お次は どうかな？
お前のお気に入りは
（アナウンス）二陣戦 東 五條(ごじょう)君
Second bout.
On the east side, Gojo-kun.
（３人）佑真さ〜ん！
（火ノ丸）相撲部に入る前は—
Yuma-san!
He was a delinquent before
he joined the sumo club.
バリバリのヤンキーでした
でも 素直なんスよ あいつ
But... his heart's in the right place.
Spirit!
（審判）はっきよい！
He was ready for the two-handed strike!
諸手突(もろてづ)き 読まれてる！
相手は 石川県の個人戦４位
瀬良拓海(たくみ)　強いです！
That guy placed fourth
in the Ishikawa tournament.
Sera Takumi is very strong.
I have to withstand
Tenma's strikes every day!
（瀬良）こっちは毎日
典馬の突き 食らってんだぜ
Come on!
（火ノ丸）あいつは…
He used to be the kind of delinquent
that shouldn't even exist anymore.
最初は ホント
今どき いるかって感じのワルで
He was king of the mountain.
お山の大将じゃった
でも ワシとの勝負で
潔く負けを認めて—
But after fighting me and acknowledging
his defeat, he bowed his head.
頭を下げたんじゃ
Humility is the key to improving.
素直な心こそ 上達のカギだ
それが
相撲と空手の融合という—
That's what makes something crazy like
combining sumo and karate possible.
ムチャな注文にも
現実味を持たせてくれる
So I'm expecting great things from him.
だから
あいつには期待しとるんです
オラーッ！
ウウッ…　速(はえ)え！
He's so fast!
Rather than pushing him, his strikes
are making the opponent bounce off.
（金盛）
押すというより はじくような突き
あいつのは
一発一発に残る衝撃が違う
Each blow is hitting him in a different way.
Even if he wanted to grab his hands,
腕を手繰ろうにも 空手由来の
引きの速さが それをさせない
the karate-like snapping is
too fast for him to do so.
そいつに連打を
許しちゃいけなかったな 瀬良
You shouldn't have let him
get up a head of steam, Sera.
うぜえんだよ この豆鉄砲が！
I've had enough of your little peashooter!
掛け突き…
Trip and strike...
Castle Break Punch!
Castle
Break
Punch
Castle
Break
Punch
Yeah!
（歓声）
（男性）すげえ！
よし！
Yes!
Yuma!
佑真〜っ！
Got 'im!
（西郷(さいごう)･橋(はし)）やった！
（舟木(ふなき)）佑真さん すげえ！
Yuma-san, that was awesome!
It looks like Kita High are down and out.
（男性１）
もう あとがねえじゃねえか 北高
Some powerhouse they are!
（男性２）情けねえ名門だな！
どちらも先行逃げきりを狙って
前半で勝負を仕掛けてきただけに
Both teams wanted to carve
out a lead in the early bouts,
so these two wins in a row are huge.
この２連勝は大きいッスね
Yes, but their opponent in the third bout...
（冴ノ山(さえのやま)）
ええ　ただ 次の中堅戦—
will be a much bigger challenge.
彼が相手となると
さすがに厳しいと思いますがね
（相沢）頼む 典馬
It's up to you, Tenma.
Not that I'm worried about
how a national treasure will fare.
（相沢）もちろん 国宝のお前に
心配なんかしてねえし—
こんな情けねえ先輩の激励なんて
要らねえことも分かってる
And I know you don't need a pep talk
from such a pathetic captain.
But just let me say it, anyway.
でも それでも言わせてくれ
Win, Tenma!
勝ってくれ 典馬！
Dammit! I'm sorry, guys.
（瀬良）くそ…　悪い みんな
（典馬）“情けないチームメート”
Pathetic teammates...
A national treasure who fails to
become a high school yokozuna...
（典馬）
“高校横綱になれない国宝”
“優勝できない 情けない名門”
A renowned school without a championship...
そういうの全部 ぶっ壊しに
来たんでしょう 俺たちは
We're here to change all that.
Yone-san. Komori-san.
Prepare for your bouts.
ヨネさん 小森(こもり)さん
準備しててくださいよ
Watch closely, you guys.
（金盛）お前ら よく見とけよ
You won't win nationals next year if you
don't come up with a plan to beat this guy.
ヤツを攻略しないことには
来年の全国制覇も かなわねえぞ
Which one are you talking about?
（沙田(さだ)）
ヤツって どっちのことッスか？
Third bout.
（アナウンス）中堅戦 東 國崎(くにさき)君
On the east side, Kunisaki-kun.
A national wrestling champion?
（蟹江）レスリング国体王者？
I see.
なるほど
でも 相撲を始めて 数か月だろう？
相手は国宝だぜ
But he's only been doing
sumo for a few months, right?
He's up against a national treasure!
I don't like to bandy this word around,
（火ノ丸）
軽々しく使いたくはないですが—
それでも
あいつの伸びを形容するには—
but there's simply no other
way to describe his talent.
この言葉以外 見つからんのです
He...
あいつは…
Kunisaki Chihiro...
（２人）國崎千比路(ちひろ)は—
...is a genius.
天才です
（千比路）身長差は20センチ以上
He's got 20 centimeters on me.
This must be what it feels
like to be Hinomaru.
これが
火ノ丸が いつも見てる景色か
How will you attack,
national treasure Odenta Mitsuyo?
さあ どう出る？　国宝 大典太光世(おおでんたみつよ)
At that distance, he's a sitting duck
for the best striker in high school sumo.
離れちまったら 高校ナンバー１の
突き押しの餌食じゃねえか
助走つけて
一気に かいくぐるつもりか？
Is he going to start at a run and go in low?
見せてもらおうじゃねえか
Show me, Kunisaki.
Show me what your talent,
which even Sada acknowledges,
沙田さえも認める國崎の才能が—
国宝を相手に
どこまで通用するのか
can do against a national treasure.
Spirit!
（審判）はっきよい！
（蛍(けい)）なんで
土俵際にいるのに突きが
How'd that strike reach him
at the edge of the ring?
Did you think he couldn't reach you
if you held back like that?
離れれば
届かないとでも思ったのかよ
Nearly the entire sumo ring is in his range.
土俵内 ほぼ全てが射程圏内
His speed and power are unmatched!
スピード パワー
全てがケタ違いの—
His lightning-quick pushing
strike: Flash Attack!
最上級の突き押し…
Flash
Attack
（典馬）シュッ！
グハッ！
Kunisaki-san is...
（蛍）あの國崎さんが…
（桐仁(きりひと)）何もさせてもらえない！？
He can't do anything!
I guess he wasn't ready to
take on a national treasure.
国宝を相手にするには
まだ早すぎたか
I know my sumo needs work if
I want to become a better fighter.
（千比路）分かってんだよ
俺が力士として未熟だってことは
コツコツ積み上げてる時間は
俺にはねえ
I don't have time to get there on my own.
So...
だったら お前の相撲を吸収して
飛び級で上に行くまでよ！
I want to absorb your sumo style
and soar straight to the top!
よし！
Yes!
まさか 最初に距離を取ったのは
日景の突きを見極めるため？
Was he holding off so he could
evaluate Hikage's strikes?
かなり食らっちゃいましたけどね
He took a real pounding, though.
The best strikes in high school sumo
were even fiercer than he was expecting.
実際に体感する高校ナンバー１の
突き押しは想像以上
見切るのに てこずるのも
当然でしょう
Of course he had a rough time
seeing through them.
ちょっと待て
Wait a second... He's completely
copied your sumo style?!
沙田の相撲そのものを ヤツは
完全にコピーしちまったってのか？
The longer you wrestle him,
the creepier he starts to feel.
あの人の相手をしていると
だんだん気味が悪くなってくる
More...
（千比路）
もっと… もっと見せろ！
Show me more!
His powers of observation more than make up
for his lack of experience in the sumo ring.
（沙田）相撲経験の浅さを
補って余りあるほどの確かな観察眼
それこそが
國崎さんの底知れぬ吸収力の正体
That's the secret of how
Kunisaki-san absorbs techniques.
不愉快ですよね
I can't stand it.
I didn't make it past the
prefectural prelims, and yet...
俺は県予選で消えたはずなのに
まるで そこに—
It's like it's me fighting.
俺がいるみたいだ
Mikazuki Munechika?
So this is the heaviest blow
in all of high school sumo?
（千比路）
これが 高校一の突き押しか
なら 俺には もう—
That means I no longer have anything to fear!
（千比路）怖いもんはねえぜ！
（典馬）ウウッ！
He outmaneuvered Odento's strike!
大典太の突きを突破した！
An over-the-shoulder belt-grab.
（佑真）
肩越しに上手(うわて)を…
I can't believe he can reach!
（蛍）
あれで届くなんて…
だが 体勢がいいのは
國崎さんのほうだ　いける！
But Kunisaki-san has the stronger stance!
He can do it!
They're probably laughing at me again.
（典馬）また笑われてるんだろうな
I'm a national treasure,
so they're expecting a lot from me,
“国宝だ何だと
さんざん期待されながら—”
but here I am, losing to a guy who
was a wrestler till a few months ago.
“この間まで
レスリングやってたヤツに—”
“翻弄されてる”ってさ
（典馬）別に俺 兄貴の相撲なんか
見たいわけじゃないんスけど
I'm not really interested
in watching my brother fight.
Aichi Prefectural Gymnasium
Professional Sumo Nagoya Tournament
He'll win enough times.
それなりに勝つのは
いつものことじゃん
Of course, he won't beat a yokozuna, no way.
どうせ 横綱には負けんでしょう
Hey!
（鈴ヶ嶽(すずがたけ)）おい！
All he cares about is
maintaining his current rank.
今の地位さえ守れてりゃ
それでいいんだろうな
ホント情けねえ
It's pathetic.
If he doesn't care about getting
better, he should just quit.
上を目指す気がないんなら
もう やめちまえばいいのに
（殴る音）
いてっ！
いって…　何スか！？
Ow...
What was that for?!
（鈴ヶ嶽）ホントに
何も分かってねえんだな お前は
You don't know what you're talking about.
I didn't think I'd hear his own
brother repeating that tripe.
実の兄弟のお前まで—
あいつらみてえなこと
言うんじゃねえよ
（男性３）ムリムリ！
どうせ 今回も勝てやしないよ！
He's got no chance!
He won't win this bout!
I gave up rooting for Daikeisho.
（男性３）俺は もう
大景勝(だいけいしょう)に期待するのは やめたの
（男性４）
なにが最強の日本人力士だよ
"Strongest Japanese sumo wrestler," my ass.
He just isn't hungry enough!
（男性３）要するに
ハングリー精神が足りんのよ
何だよ？　これ
What's going on here?
This place isn't as comfortable
for the ozeki as you think.
お前が思ってるほど—
ここは大関にとって
居心地のいい場所じゃねえよ
だったら なおさら
どうして辞めねえんだよ？
Even more reason, then.
Why doesn't he just quit?
（鈴ヶ嶽）決まってんだろう
Isn't that obvious?
Because he isn't broken yet.
（鈴ヶ嶽）まだ折れてないからだよ
Maybe the reason the ozeki
looks broken to you
（鈴ヶ嶽）お前の目に
大関が折れたように見えるのは…
is because you are.
お前のほうが
折れてるからじゃないのか？
You've been looking away from your brother
because you see himself in him.
（鈴ヶ嶽）
兄貴から目をそらし続けてるのは
重なるからだろう
You believe your brother
can't beat a yokozuna
横綱に勝てない兄貴と
天王寺(てんのうじ)に勝てない自分が
because you can't beat Tennoji.
Maybe you could learn
a thing or two by watching him.
あの背中にこそ 学ぶべきものが
あるんじゃないのか？
Your brother's a strong man.
お前の兄貴は強い男だよ
情けねえのは俺だ
I'm the pathetic one.
鬼丸も同じ目をしてた
Onimaru had that same look in his eyes.
The look of someone who is confronting
a reality that threatens to break them.
折れそうな現実にも顔を背けず
前に進み続ける者の目
俺は それにイラついて
当たり散らしてただけだ
All I did was get annoyed
and take it out on others.
I'm a real loser.
最低だぜ ホントに
I want to be a strong sumo
wrestler like my brother!
俺もなりたい
兄貴のような強い力士に
A backward twisting overarm throw!
あの状態から なんてリーチだ！
From that stance?! What reach he has!
He's so close!
（蛍）至近距離！
（佑真）マズイ！
Crap!
He's coming at me even stronger than before!
（千比路）
どんどん強く むけやがる！
I guess that's why he's a national treasure!
それでこそ国宝だぜ！
I'm going to eat you and
smash through my own limits!
てめえを食って
俺も限界を超える！
A feint?!
フェイント！？
High-Angle
Head Chop
High-Angle Head Chop!
Lightning!
Lightning
（千比路）ガハッ！
So this is Dachi High's Kunisaki, huh?
（駿海(しゅんかい)）ダチ高の國崎といったか
なるほど　すさまじい才気だが—
I see.
He has an incredibly sharp mind,
but he's not ready to beat Hikage Tenma.
今は まだ日景典馬に及ばない
いや
Yet...
Perhaps that's why he challenged him.
だからこそ挑んだのか
大相撲の世界でも—
Even in professional sumo,
there are those who evolve rapidly
following an upset win.
たったひとつの金星をきっかけに
大きく飛躍する者がいる
He's trying to break out of his shell.
殻を破ろうとしているんだ
挑むだけでは足りぬ
Just fighting him isn't enough.
Only an upset will take him
to greater heights!
金星こそが糧となる
Strongest!
（千比路）最強！
（典馬）ンンーッ！
Yes!
（一同）よし！
He was grabbed first!
先に差された！
His right hand's inside,
and his left is high!
右下手に左ハズ　組み手 十分！
The perfect grip!
Go, Tenma!
（瀬良）いけー！
（相沢）典馬ーっ！
You're working on the cross-grip sumo style.
（沙田）
國崎さんが目指す相撲は—
どっちかっていうと
四つ相撲でしょう？
そのわりには
廻(まわ)しに対する執着が少ないんだよな
So why do you ignore
the mawashi belt so much?
正直 なに考えてるのか
分からなくて怖いんだけど
Honestly, I can't tell what
you're thinking, which scares me.
（千比路）
突き押しだとか 四つだとか—
All that thrust-and-push,
cross-grip, whatever...
If I get caught up in
worrying about that stuff,
そうやって くくられちまったら
その道のスペシャリストである—
I won't be able to beat
specialists like you.
お前らには
到底 追いつけねえだろう
“なに考えてるのか
分からなくて怖い”？
You're scared because you
can't tell what I'm thinking?
結構じゃねえか
俺が目指してんのは—
That's perfect.
I want my sumo style... to be unsettling!
そういう不気味な相撲だ！
（典馬）うん？　何をしてる？
What's he doing?
What is this dark aura?!
何だ？　この気配は
I want to be stronger! Stronger!
（千比路）
強くなりてえんだ　もっと強く！
So... I'm going to... cause an upset!
だから この金星は—
ぜってえ もらう！
That move!
（桐仁）あれは…
（小関）まさか…
It can't be!
（千比路）
ネオ･チヒロスペシャル１号…
Neo Chihiro Special #1:
Shoot
Down
Shoot Down!
Shoot
Down
（男性１）
去年の３位を倒しやがった！
He beat last year's third-placed finisher!
Dachi High's on fire!
（男性２）ダチ高 やべえ！
（歓声）
People who let common sense
dictate their actions
（火ノ丸）常識に縛られたヤツらは
国宝と自分たちの間に壁を作る
place a wall between themselves
and national treasures.
They believe national treasures are special,
and there's no way they can beat them.
“国宝は特別で 自分たちでは
国宝には勝てないんだ”と
でも あいつには
壁なんてないんです
But he doesn't have any walls.
あるのは距離だけ
All he has is distance.
だから
何も恐れず 全力で駆け抜ける
That's why he can charge
forward without fear.
That's the kind of person
who causes an upset.
そういうヤツの所に 金星は
転がり込むんじゃないスかね
Uh, a kimono-string drop...
（アナウンス）え〜 襷反(たすきぞ)り
襷反りで 東 國崎君の勝ち
Kunisaki-kun on the east side
wins with a kimono-string drop.
A kimono-string drop? The heck is that?
襷反り？　何だ？　それ
Wait, you used a powerful technique even the
pros rarely use without knowing what it was?
大相撲でも
めったに出ない大技を—
知らずに
やったっていうんですか？
It's instinct...
本能だ
本能で動いたとしか思えない
He must've moved purely on instinct.
とんでもねえ野郎だな
You're one scary dude.
相撲技でありながら
相撲の常識から外れた決まり手
It's a sumo technique,
but one that defies the norms.
正に國崎さんを象徴する技だ
It fits Kunisaki-san to a T.
My national treasure name?
（千比路）俺の国宝名？
（沙田）そうッスよ
Yeah, man. If you beat a national treasure,
国宝に勝つ実力があるんなら
そいつも国宝でしょう
you should be one, too.
That's stupid.
バ〜カ　国宝っていうのは
横綱候補を指す呼び名だろうが
National treasures are those guys
who try to become yokozuna.
俺のゴールは
あくまで総合格闘技の頂点よ
I want to be the best mixed martial artist.
（千比路）まあ どうしても
二つ名を付けてえってんなら—
But if I had to choose a moniker,
then I suppose...
そうだな…
“国宝喰(ぐ)いの國崎千比路”
…とでも呼んでもらおうか！
Call me Kunisaki Chihiro,
the "National Treasure Eater"!
Ushio!
（小関）潮！
"The National Treasure Eater."
国宝喰い　英語で言うとＫ･Ｉ･Ｄ
“キッド”だ
Or, in English: K-I-D. The kid!
National Treasure is Delicious!
〝国宝･イズ･
デリシャス〞
Next Bout  "The One Loved by the Sumo Gods"
（部員たち）
あ〜　おう…